RICHA SHAURBH

2400 4th Ave #567 Seattle WA 98121

+1 (206) 953-3929 richa.shaurabh@gmail.com

<u>richasha.github.io/Portfolio</u> linkedin.com/in/richa-shaurabh

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Web/Frontend Developer with more than 4 years of professional experience and expertise in a wide array of frontend technologies, like HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, React.js, etc. demonstrated in onsite & offshore industrial projects spanning the telecom domain to home automation.

EDUCATION

SRM University, Chennai, India

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics Engineering

Patna Women's College Graduated in 2008

Higher Secondary School

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming skills: Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS, React.js, HTML, CSS, SASS, Ruby, PostgreSQL

Testing Frameworks: Jasmine, Karma

Tools: Git, npm, Sublime Text

OS Experience: MacOS, Windows

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Apr 2015 – Jul 2017 Bangalore, India

2008-2012

GPA: 7.8 / 10.0

Software Developer

LG Soft India

- Development of "Enact" which is LG's next generation Javascript framework based on React.js. It is used for developing native-quality HTML5 apps that can run on any device.
- Firefox Mobile OS development for LG Fx0 phone Developed & optimized the Camera & Gallery apps, atop the Gaia User Interface application, using Object Oriented Javascript.

Tech Mahindra

Nov 2013 – Apr 2015

Software Developer

Bangalore, India & Sydney, Australia

- Optus Mobile Network Coverage & Diagnosis application Designed & developed a frontend application that showed network tower diagnosis information on a map to customers of Optus (Australian telecom). It also let customers log complaints against specific towers and get responses from Optus Engineers.
- Technologies used: Javascript, AngularJS & the OpenLayers library.

FLORET Media Jan 2013 - Nov 2013

Web Developer

Bangalore, India

• Responsive website development for online marketing of FLORET Media clients using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery & AngularJS.

CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Epicodus Certified "Web and Mobile Development" engineer Met all the certification requirements: Javascript, AngularJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Ruby and PostgreSQL.
- Sports Awarded by the State government for winning in the Throwball league for the state of Bihar, India

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Doctors Search An interface that allows users to search for Doctors in a certain area based on a medical condition, doctor's name and other similar search criteria using the BetterDoctor API.
- Mykart An eCommerce website with user interfaces to show product details, product listings and shopping carts.

2017